Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have part two
of a very important and very valuable
series about giving presentations.
That's right.
As you well know, we started this series.
It's a ten-part series and
today we're going to talk about
sales and charts and graphs
and more or less explaining
maybe a PowerPoint presentation.
That's right. So you're going to learn some
wonderful ways of talking about
changes in markets and marketing.
So let's take a listen to
today's dialogue and we'll
be back in a moment to
talk about what you've heard.
As all of you are well aware, competition
in the laptop computer sector is intense.
We continue to fight
with our competitors for
market share and this is the case both
in the developed markets in the west
as well as more developing
markets in Asia and Africa.
You may ask yourself why
is this market so cutthroat?
Well, the answer is simple. There is a
huge untapped potential market out there
with a huge untapped potential for profit.
If I bring up the first graph here, it
shows the increase in terms of number
of computer owners across the globe.
As you can see in the 1980s,
computer ownership amounted to
around 0.5% of the total world population.
Since the 1990s, computer
ownership has risen dramatically.
In the new millennium, we
saw an even larger explosion
in computer owners with
figures rising to around 4-5%.
An increase of 1,000%
compared with the 1980s.
If we move on to discuss the
figures for China specifically,
we can see in chart B that the overall
figure for computer ownership stands at
around 60 million, which represents a
huge increase in a very short time period.
Now of course, 60
million is just a drop in the
ocean if you compare the
total population of China.
And this is a key reason why the personal
computer market is such a hot market.
For us at Alpha and of course
for all of our competitors as well,
we have millions of
potential customers who
are looking to join
the internet generation.
If we do this right, we really can
repute rewards in a very short time frame.
I now like to move on to
discuss the X420 brand itself
and compare and contrast
with some of our key competitors.
All right, we're back.
So now let's start with language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay, so in the first
part of what Mr. Ford is
saying, he mentioned
something called market share.
Now, Margot, what is market share?
That's right.
Everyone is competing for market share.
And this is basically a small
portion of your available market.
So for example, if you sell perfumes,
women's perfume, then your market shares
may be women who are 18 to 35 years old
in your city or in your
town or in your country.
I see, right.
So when we're talking
about market share
because we're sharing
a piece of this big pie,
we're going to talk about
that in terms of a percentage.
So 30% or 15%.
That's right.
I think maybe one of the clearest
examples is Coca Cola has, I think,
maybe a 60% market share of
the carbonated beverages market.
Interesting. So you could
say that Apple has a 50%
market share of the
personal computing industry.
That's right.
Very good.
So this is what we
referred to as market share.
Now, as we continue to talk about markets,
we have two very interesting
words when we referred
to a developed market
and a developing market.
Okay.
So a developed market is something
that has been polished and grown over time.
Perhaps we talk about the developed
world being Western Europe and America.
But then we have developing markets.
And those are markets that are still trying
to figure out kind of what's going on.
They're growing.
They're usually growing much
faster than a developed market.
That's right.
So again, when we're talking
about maybe computers,
we consider, for example, the
United States, a developed market.
Many people already have a computer
or express the desire to buy one.
And so maybe a developing
market are some of the
African countries where
they're still growing.
And so now they're they're beginning
to to purchase more and more computers.
Okay.
So developed and developing two
different ways to describe markets.
That's right.
Now, after that, we hear
this phrase, cutthroat.
So someone asks, why is
this market so cutthroat?
What does this mean?
A cutthroat business
or a cutthroat industry.
It means that it's very, very competitive.
Okay, so cutthroat we're
actually talking about maybe
having a knife and cutting
someone else's throat.
But it's just a metaphor.
It's a way of saying, yes,
this is very competitive.
So you're not actually
cutting someone's throat.
Everyone is fighting for that market share.
So it's very cutthroat.
Everyone is fighting very, very hard.
But you're not literally killing
someone or cutting their throats.
And you could even use this
to talk about a sporting event.
You could say, you know,
it was a cutthroat game.
That's right.
That's right, so anything that's
very competitive or very close.
So to finish off language
takeaway when Mr.
Ford was towards the
end of his presentation,
he said that the rewards could be
very, very big in a very short time frame.
So when we say the word time
frame, we mean period of time.
It's not like 2 p.m.
It's like from from May to June.
We have this short time frame.
It's only two months long.
So time frame is a window or a period.
That's right.
So this is what he is referring to is
that in a very short period or in this
period of time, they could
make a lot of money a time frame.
Right.
But how long would a long time
frame be maybe a couple of years?
All right.
So you can have a short time
frame and a long time frame.
That's right.
Okay.
Why don't we take a
look at our dialogue again
and we'll be back shortly
with Fluency Builder.
As all of you are well aware, competition
in the laptop computer sector is intense.
We continue to fight with our
competitors for market share.
And this is the case both in the
developed markets in the West,
as well as more developing
markets in Asia and Africa.
You may ask yourself, why
is this market so cutthroat?
Well, the answer is simple.
There is a huge untapped
potential market out
there with a huge
untapped potential for profit.
If I bring up the first
graph here, it shows
the increase in terms of number of
computer owners across the globe.
As you can see in the
1980s, computer ownership
amounted to around 0.5%
of the total world population.
Since the 1990s, computer
ownership has risen dramatically.
In the new millennium, we
saw an even larger explosion in
computer owners with figures
rising to around 4% to 5%.
An increase of 1,000%
compared with the 1980s.
If we move on to discuss the
figures for China specifically,
we can see in chart B
that the overall figure for
computer ownership
stands at around 60 million,
which represents a huge
increase in a very short time period.
Now of course, 60
million is just a drop in the
ocean if you compare the
total population of China.
And this is a key reason why the personal
computer market is such a hot market.
For us at Alpha and of course
for all of our competitors as well,
we have millions of
potential customers who
are looking to join
the internet generation.
If we do this right, we really can reap
huge rewards in a very short time frame.
I now like to move on to
discuss the X420 brand itself
and compare and contrast
with some of our key competitors.
All right, we're back.
So now we've picked out a
couple of different phrases for you.
Let's check those out
now on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
So in today's dialogue, we heard
Mr. Ford talk about some numbers.
He's talking about growth
and change in the market.
And he says with figures two
around four to five percent,
we've got an overall
increase of 1,000 percent.
That's right.
So this phrase an increase
of very, very common
when you're talking about
growth of maybe revenue
or when you're talking about the
growth of a company or sales, for example.
So it's important to remember
here that this is a fixed phrase, we say,
an increase of 10 percent
or an increase of 30 percent.
But you can use the same phrase
with drops in percentages or money.
So you can say a decrease of 10 percent.
That means that you go down 10
percent or a decrease of 100 percent.
That's right.
So a very useful phrase when talking
about incrementing someone or, as you said,
decreasing a decrease of five percent.
Now, Mr. Ford used a very interesting
phrase when referring to the Chinese market.
Obviously, it's a very big market.
And he says that the computer
ownership stands at around 60 million.
But of course, 60 million
is just a drop in the ocean,
if you compare it to
the population of China.
That's right.
So what does this mean?
It's a big percentage
or a small percentage.
Very, very small.
All right. So what he's saying here is
it's like a drop of water in an ocean.
So a drop of water is so
small you don't even notice it.
You don't even see it
because the ocean is so big.
And so you can use this
in many different ways.
You can say, hey, you know, five
dollars is just a drop in the ocean.
It's not really important
because it's very little money.
That's right.
So it's sort of like a metaphor
saying, you know what?
It's very significant.
It's just a drop of water in an ocean.
It's not really something you can notice.
That's right.
Just a drop in the ocean.
And now at the very end of today's speech,
we heard the phrase
to compare and contrast.
So we're talking about the
X420 computer brand itself.
Now, what does Mr. Ford mean
when he says to compare and contrast?
So when we mentioned the word compare,
we are basically trying to determine
how they are similar in many ways.
The characteristics of
how they are similar and
to contrast is how
they are different, right?
That's right.
So let's let's use an example perhaps
we could say Pepsi and Coca-Cola.
Let's compare and contrast.
So they're both carbonated beverages.
They are both sweet and they're
both they're pretty much the same color.
That's right.
And they're also fairly cheap.
They have about the same price.
But I would say that Coca-Cola
is tastes more like prune.
So that would be a
contrasting characteristic of
Coca-Cola is that maybe
it tastes a little bit sweeter.
It does.
And you could also say
it's easier to find Coca-Cola.
Pepsi is less, less easy to find sometimes.
That's right.
Another way that they're different.
So basically to compare
and contrast is to point out
how two things are similar
and how they're different.
That's right.
So we've had a lot of
interesting phrases there.
I think very useful if you're talking
about business and marketing and sales.
So why don't we listen to
our dialogue one last time.
As all of you are well aware, competition
in the laptop computer sector is intense.
We continue to fight with our
competitors from market share.
And this is the case both in the
developed markets in the West,
as well as more developing
markets in Asia and Africa.
You may ask yourself, why
is this market so cutthroat?
Well, the answer is simple.
There is a huge untapped
potential market out
there with a huge
untapped potential for profit.
If I bring up the first graph
here, it shows the increase
in terms of number of computer
owners across the globe.
As you can see in the
1980s, computer ownership
amounted to around 0.5%
of the total world population.
Since the 1990s, computer
ownership has risen dramatically.
In the new millennium, we
saw an even larger explosion
in computer owners with
figures rising to around 4-5%.
An increase of 1,000%
compared with the 1980s.
If we move on to discuss the
figures for China specifically,
we can see in chart B
that the overall figure
for computer ownership
stands at around 60
million, which represents a huge
increase in a very short time period.
Now of course, 60
million is just a drop in the
ocean if you compare the
total population of China.
And this is a key reason why the personal
computer market is such a hot market.
For us at Alfa and of course
for all of our competitors as well,
we have millions of
potential customers who
are looking to join
the internet generation.
If we do this right, we really can
repute rewards in a very short time frame.
I now like to move on to
discuss the X420 brand itself and
compare and contrast with
some of our key competitors.
All right, we're back.
So as we mentioned, this is just
a part of our presentation series.
We're going to keep on talking with
Mr. Ford as he discusses business and a lot
of other very interesting and
useful skills for talking in public.
That's right.
So the goal of this
series is to help you
feel better when you're
giving a presentation in English.
We all know it's very,
very hard to talk in
English when you're
when you're still learning,
but it's even harder to talk alone
to give a speech or a presentation.
And so the point of
this series is to really
give you those skills
and to help teach you
some of the key phrases
and words that you'll
be using in your
presentations in the future.
That's right.
So if you have any questions or any doubts,
we are always available at Englishpot.
com and we'll see
everyone there.
Bye.